hello my name is Liz in this lesson I'm
going to look at the types of topics
that the examiner could ask you in IELTS
speaking part one and at the end of this
lesson I'll give you a link so that you
can take a look at the topics and
questions for yourself the examiner will
probably ask you about 12 different
questions in speaking part 1 and these
questions come from usually three
different topics these topics are all
familiar topics they're topics that are
common to everybody throughout the world
now the first topic of these three
usually comes from one of these work
study home or hometown you will probably
get one of them for your first topic
work or study now if the examiner
decides to ask you about work or study
the first question that the examiner
will ask is do you work or do you study
now the examiner is asking this question
only because he or she needs to know
which topic to choose to ask the
questions
so with this question you do not need to
expand your answer you can just say very
clearly I work I study now if you're a
student and you finished university but
you're not working either then you need
to tell the examiner that and you need
to say I've just finished University but
I don't have a job yet and the examiner
will then continue and ask you about the
topic of study
now with these topics the common
questions that the examiner could ask
you is often where do you study or work
why did you choose that subject or that
job the examiner might ask you about
your first day about
people that you work with or study with
and other things about your work or your
studies now for the topic of home this
topic is all about where you live so it
could be about your house or your
apartment and in that topic the examiner
can ask you about the rooms in the house
how they are decorated so what you can
see on the walls or what kind of views
you have from the windows the examiner
might also ask you about the people you
live with or the area and street that
you live in and the last topic hometown
now if you get the topic of hometown
this is about the place where you were
born or where you spent most of your
childhood and for this topic the
examiner often asks you about places in
your hometown for example buildings or
old buildings in your hometown
the examiner might ask you about the
weather or transportation in your
hometown or if you plan to still live
there in the future
so those are usually one of those will
be your first topic for IELTS speaking
part one but you have two more topics
after this so let's have a look at what
kind of topics you can get next here is
a list of 18 different topics I would
like you to have a look at the list and
decide which ones you think you might be
asked about in IELTS speaking part one
do you think the examiner might ask you
about all of them or only some of them
well let's have a look we've got family
friends hobbies weather happiness sport
food clothes school flowers shopping
computers going out
newspapers childhood holidays
dictionaries and transport do you think
it's possible to get all of them in
IELTS speaking part one well I will tell
you that all these topics are possible
in IELTS speaking part one I know that
many people may have read or heard that
topics in IELTS speaking part one are
all easy unfortunately they are not all
easy you can see here the topic of
happiness or flowers or dictionaries
sometimes the topics can be challenging
so one of the keys to preparing for
IELTS speaking part one is to prepare
topics and that means to prepare ideas
and vocabulary for all the different
topics for IELTS speaking so this is a
list of some of the topics you can get
in IELTS speaking part one if you would
like to see more topics and questions as
well please follow the link here and
that will take you to my blog
WWL is calm and in the blog you will
find that there are topics and questions
for part 1 part 2 and part 3 of the
IELTS speaking test well that's all for
this lesson I will see you again in
another Isles lesson
you